# Maheen Khan

## **Software Developer**

- @ pakhtar635@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/maheen-akhtar-khan-377082267
- https://github.com/mkhan429419/
- Islamabad, Pakistan
- thttps://mkhan429419.github.io/Portfolio-Site/

## **SUMMARY**

Software Engineering student with a strong enthusiasm for web development. Have worked through bootcamps on JavasScript, Node, React, MERN, and other emerging technologies. I enjoy building websites and solutions that diversify the user experience. Most proud of my recent project GreenThread - an online market I developed in my sophomore year that is designed to promote small businesses and sustainable fashion.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Primary & Secondary

The International School of Choueifat (Abu Dhabi)

## **Bachelors of Software Engineering**

National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST)

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Web Developement Intern

#### CodSoft

https://github.com/mkhan429419/CODSOFT

CodSoft offers IT services and IT consultancy that specializes in creating innovative solutions for businesses.

- · Completed 3 tasks on Web Development with HTML, CSS, and JS.
- Task 1: A personal portfolio site, showcasing all my skills, projects, and resume
- Task 2: To-do list site, allowing users to add, delete, and edit their tasks. The tasks are stored and fetched from the backend.
- Task 3: Calculator, with an interactive interface for buttons, utilizing CSS grid layout. Event listeners, statements, operators, and loops were used to handle user input and perform calculations.

# Front-End Web Development Intern

#### DPL

苗 06/2024 👂 Islamabad, Pakistan - Onsite

A https://github.com/mkhan429419/DataHub

DPL is one of the leading software development and IT companies around the world. Established in 2003, DPL serves customers in all major regions emphasizing most on Europe, Middle East and Americas.

- Worked with a supervisor to develop DataHub, a file management system that utilizes modern tech stacks and securely stores the users data using AWS.
- Utilized MERN stack for development, including React, Typescript, and TailwindCSS for the frontend, Node and Express for backend, and MongoDB for the database. Files were handled securely using AWS S3, and JWT was used for token-based authentication.
- Learned modern deployment methods: frontend was deployed on vercel, backend on heroku, and database on MongoDB Atlas.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML	CSS	Java	JavaScript
jQuery	React	Node	Express
Tailwind	CSS	AWS	MongoDB
MERN	Full-S	tack Web	Development
TypeScri	pt B	ootstrap	

## **PROJECTS**

#### GreenThread

- Developed in my sophomore year as a Database Systems project with 2 fellow students.
- GreenThread is an ecommerce platform that offers multi-level authentication, with a separate user and admin frontend. It allows users to view products, add and delete products from cart, place orders, send inquiries to admins, and view blog posts.
- Admins have access to a comprehensive dashboard where they can view order and user statistics, and manage various categories.
- Utilized MERN stack for development. JWT was used for token-based authentication, and React-Redux library for state management.
- I worked specifically on the admin frontend, and overall backend of the project.
- Deployed on netlify, with database deployed on MongoDB Atlas.

#### DataHub

https://github.com/mkhan429419/DataHub

DataHub is an intuitive platform that provides file management services, with features like secure registration, personal storage, and an admin dashboard for tracking file activities.

- Solo project developed during my onsite summer internship at DPL, Islamabad.
- DataHub has a layout similar to Google Drive, including functionalities for user registration, login, personal storage (CRUD operations on files), account settings, and an admin dashboard for file statistics.
- Utilized MERN stack for development, including React, Typescript, and TailwindCSS for the frontend. Files were handled securely using AWS S3, and JWT was used for token-based authentication.
- Frontend was deployed on vercel, backend on heroku, and database on MongoDB Atlas.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Web Development & Designing Intern

#### **The Sparks Foundation**

# 07/2024 - Present Singapore - Remotely

The Sparks Foundation works to bring parity in education, making sure children have an equal opportunity at success, irrespective of their financial background.

## Front-End Web Development Intern

#### **Interns Pakistan**

iii 06/2024 - 07/2024 ♀ Pakistan - Remotely

Interns Pakistan provides students with the opportunities, support, and mentorship needed to launch their careers.

## **VOLUNTEERING**

#### **Executive Finance**

#### **NUST ACM Student Chapter**

As a finance executive in the NUST ACM society, I am presented with many opportunities to further my skills and collaborate closely with my fellow executives. I am mainly responsible for keeping track of expenditures on different departments throughout the year.

# **LANGUAGES**

**English** Native



Urdu Proficient



#### **French**

Intermediate



## **PROJECTS**

#### Searchify

**iii** 11/2023 - 12/2023

NUST, Islamabad

Phttps://github.com/tehreemahmad149/DSAProject Searchify is an elementary search engine, tailored to harness the extensive NELA-GT 2022 dataset.

- Developed in my sophomore year as a Data Structures & Algorithms project with 2 fellow
- Inspired by Larry Page and Sergey Brin's research paper on the initial version of Google. It supports single and multi-word searches, and ranks results based on an implemented algorithm. It also provides a user-friendly interface for searching and adding new content.
- Utilized python for development, and Django for the frontend.
- I worked specifically on the system frontend, and algorithm development on the backend.

# TRAINING / COURSES

The Complete JavaScript Course 2024 (Udemy)

**Complete React Developer ZTM (Udemy)** 

**Complete Web Development Course ZTM** (Udemy)

**Machine Learning Specialization (Coursera)**